VICENTE ORTIZ

(Web || JavaScript) Developer

vicente.ogc@gmail.com Github LinkedIn



I am a +5 years of experience developer. I started my professional career specialized in fronted and that is the realm that I am passionate about. But trying to be more versatile, I am evolving widen my knowledge working as a fullstack developer daily taking part in the decision process and searching for solutions in the whole development process. I consider myself an autonomous, problem solver and proactive person while also being a team player and collaborative. All along this time I have been lucky enough to be surrounded by great people from whom I have learned a lot and developed my skills not only in the workplace but also with some side projects.

EXPERIENCE

Fullstack developer at Lansweeper

July 2019 - Nowadays

In this adventure I take part in the team in charge of creating an IT assets management SaaS solution. This software is developed with React on the front; node microservices on the backends; graphQL, gRPC and kafka for communication and kubernetes for infraestructure. All of this stick together with CI/CD on github and tests. In this position I find new challenges everyday like focusing on performance and scalability when coding, creating POCs quickly and working with distributed teams across the globe.

Fullstack developer at **Everis**

Juny 2016 - July 2019

I have worked on several projects, both for external clients and internal tools, in which I have used jQuery, Angular, Java, Spring, REST architectures, MySQL, MongoDB, git and Atlassian suite among others.

- I promoted in less than a year while working for a national insurance company.
- I was in constant communication with the client and adapting our solution to their needs.
- I managed several services and tools used across the whole company all around the world, I supported users, solved tickets and developed new features.
- I grew up as a mentor helping new colleagues and giving talks and workshops to the rest of the employees in the center about rising technologies.

VOLUNTEERING

Volunteering at **Everis**

July 2016 - July 2019

I have been an altruistic member of the organization in Alicante of several events such as <u>Women Tech Makers</u> or <u>Hash Code</u>, both planned by Google or <u>Space Apps Challenge</u> convoked by NASA. At the same time I work on side projects, personal and with other colleagues, exploring other technologies such as Amazon Web Services or Docker.

Qubic 2012 - 2017

Senior member of this student assosiaction dedicated to organize workshops and technical expositions, organize events in spanish univeersities and build engineering projects.

SKILLS

Technical

Javascript/Typescript/Node

React/Angular

HTML/CSS

REST/GraphQL

MongoDB/SQL

Soft

Agile methodologies

Teamwork

LANGUAGES

Spanish - Native

English - B2, Cambridge First (FCE)

EDUCATION

Electronics Engineering

University of Castilla La Mancha - 2015